<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on A. Samuel-Rosa</title>
    <link>http://samuel-rosa.github.io/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on A. Samuel-Rosa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>pt-br</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://samuel-rosa.github.io/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stacked generalization of statistical learners -- a case study with soil iron content in Brazil</title>
      <link>http://samuel-rosa.github.io/talk/pedometrics-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://samuel-rosa.github.io/talk/pedometrics-2017/</guid>
      <description>Resumo When modeling soil-landscape relationships we generally test a handful of statistical learners. Having limited data, we use cross-validation to select the best performing learner. In this study we evaluate the benefits of combining learners for soil prediction using stacked generalization. It consists of calibrating multiple learners and submitting them to 10-fold cross-validation. Cross-validation predictions are used as covariates in an interceptless linear regression of the target variable. Constrained to be non-negative, the estimated regression coefficients are the stacking weights expressing the importance of each learner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Public Repository of Open Soil Iron Data for Brazil</title>
      <link>http://samuel-rosa.github.io/talk/bspm-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://samuel-rosa.github.io/talk/bspm-2017/</guid>
      <description>Resumo We have recently stimulated the emergence of an unprecedented collaborative effort among soil scientists from all over Brazil. The goal: to build a centralized, public and free repository of standardized and georeferenced soil iron data with national coverage. Many Brazilian soil scientists have already shared datasets, some of them even before we could insert the datasets in possession of our institutions in what we called the Brazilian Soil Iron Data Repository (Fe-BR).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>